Joey? Are you in there?
喬伊，你在嗎？
-That's Rachel. -You have to talk to her.
-是瑞秋 -你得跟她談一談
I can't. Not after the other night. It's too weird.
不行，經過那晚的事之後 感覺真的太奇怪了
Don't tell her I'm here.
別告訴她我在這裡
Don't eat that!
別吃那個
-Hey! -Hey, Rachel.
-嘿 -嘿，瑞秋
Is Joey here?
喬伊在嗎？
-I don't see him. You? -No.
-我沒有看到他，你呢？ -沒有
Maybe he's in the sugar bowl. Joey? Nope.
或許他在糖碗裡 喬伊？沒有
Well, at least you make each other laugh.
至少 你們能逗彼此笑
-What's up? -I haven't seen him since he said..
-怎麼了？ -我一直沒見過他，自從他說…
how he, you know..
他怎麼…你們知道的…
I don't know, I think he's avoiding me.
我不知道 我想他在避我
Why is that bagel on the floor?
為什麼地板上會有貝果？
-We were playing a game. -Was Chandler naked?
-我們在玩遊戲？ -錢德沒穿衣服嗎？
Sort of like a ring-toss kind of situation?
像是在玩 套圈圈遊戲嗎？
-Sure! -What? No! No!
-沒錯 -什麼？不
All right, listen. If you see Joey, will you just tell him that..?
好吧，聽著，如果你們看到喬伊 能不能告訴他…
Tell him I miss him.
告訴他我很想他
-Okay. Did you hear that? -Yeah. That naked bagel game?
-好吧，你聽到了嗎？ -是啊，裸體貝果遊戲？
Dude, I don't know. That's a pretty small hole.
我不知道 那個洞真的很小
-You've gotta talk to her. -I can't.
-你得跟她談一談 -我沒辦法
You guys don't know what it's like to get shot down.
你們不知道 被拒絕的感覺有多難受
I don't know what that's like?
我不知道那種感覺？
Until I was 25, I thought the response to "I love you" was "Oh, crap."
我在25歲前一直以為 「我愛你」的反應是「喔，天啊」
No rejection?
我沒有被拒絕過？
I got shot down at fat camp.
我在減肥營時被拒絕過
Boy, kids are mean when they're hungry.
天啊，飢餓的孩子們 真的很殘忍
So, what do I do?
我該怎麼辦？
It's Rachel. You're gonna never talk to her again?
她是瑞秋 你永遠都不要跟她說話嗎？
It's weird and it's awkward, but you gotta at least try.
那很奇怪，也很可怕 但至少你得試試看
Yeah, okay.
好吧
I forgot this was on your..
我忘了這個曾套在你的…
We didn't play it!
我們沒有玩它
The One With The Tea Leaves
本集播出：茶葉算命法
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
（中央公園 咖啡館）
I'll look at your tea leaves and tell your fortune.
我會看你們的茶葉 幫你們算命
-You read tea leaves? -I've done it for years.
-你會茶葉算命法？ -我這麼做有好幾年
I actually stopped because I was so accurate.
後來我放棄 因為我算得太準了
And one of the great joys of life..
生命的樂趣 之一…
is its wondrous unpredictability, you know?
就是 不可預測性
And also, tea tends to give me the trots.
還有 茶葉會讓我拉肚子
-Okay. I'm done. Read mine. -Okay.
-我好了，幫我算吧 -好的
I see a ladder.
我看見一個梯子
Which can mean either a promotion or a violent death.
它的意思不是升職 就是暴力死亡
I'm the head chef. I can't get promoted.
我是主廚 我不可能被升職
Who's next?
下一個是誰？
I'm done. Do mine.
我好了，幫我算
Okay.
好吧
Oh! Okay, I see a circle.
好吧，我看到一個圈圈
Which can either mean you're having a baby..
那表示 你懷了孩子
or you'll make a scientific discovery!
或你會做出科學發現
Well, I have been spending a lot of time in the lab.
我一直都待在實驗室裡
-What does yours say, Pheebs? -All right.
-你的茶葉又告訴你什麼呢？菲比 -好吧
Wow! Yay!
哇，耶
Oh, I'm gonna meet a guy! And really soon!
我會認識一個男人 而且很快
He's gonna be the man of my dreams.
他會是我的夢中情人
Probably not the guy I had a dream about last night.
或許他不是 我昨晚夢到的那個男人
Has anyone seen my shirt?
有人看到我的襯衫嗎？
It's a button-down, like a faded salmon color?
它是前開式的襯衫 淡鮭魚色
You mean your pink shirt?
你是說你的粉紅色襯衫嗎？
Faded salmon color?
淡鮭魚色？
No, I haven't seen your pink shirt.
不，我沒有看到你的粉紅色襯衫
I must have left it at Mona's. I knew it!
我一定把它丟在蒙娜家了 我就知道
I'm sure you can get another one at Ann Taylor's.
我想你可以到安泰勒的專賣店 再買一件
That's my favorite shirt. I love it.
它是我最喜歡的襯衫 我愛它
Ask Mona to give it back.
請蒙娜把它還給你
I don't know. I could.
我不知道，或許吧
We didn't really end things on good terms.
我們不算是 好聚好散
If I went, I'd be ignoring the one thing she asked me to do..
我想去她家 就得忘了她告訴我的一件事…
jump up my own ass and die.
她要我去跳樓自殺
Oh, wait a second, you guys?
等一下
I've been seeing that guy everywhere I go.
我走到哪裡 都會看到那個男人
We take the same bus, go to the same bookstore.
我們搭同一班公車 去同一家書局
Maybe he's the tea guy.
或許他就是我的真命天子
Did you see that?
你們看到了嗎？
He totally checked you out! And he is so cute!
他真的在看你 而且他很帥
Mine is a picture of the Village People. What does that mean?
我的茶葉出現鄉巴佬的圖案 那是什麼意思？
Hi.
嗨
Hey.
嘿
-Hi. -Hi.
-嗨 -嗨
Tea gives Phoebe the trots!
茶葉讓菲比拉肚子
I thought Joey and l would be okay..
我以為 喬伊跟我可以不尷尬…
but we don't know how to be together.
但我們不知道該怎麼相處
By the way, I've been meaning to say this.
還有 我一直都想這麼說
If you guys knew about this, a heads-up would have been nice.
如果你們知道這件事 我真的很希望你們提醒我一下
Just a little, you know.
只要給點提示就夠了
"Joey loves you. Be prepared."
「喬伊愛你 做好準備」
-Sorry. -Well, for next time.
-抱歉 -下次別再犯了
-It's tough, but things will improve. -How do you know?
-那真的很難，但情況會有改善的 -你怎麼知道？
What if it gets worse and worse..
如果情況惡化…
to the point where we can't be in the same room?
我們無法共處一室呢？
I'm not great at the advice.
我不善於給好建議
Can I interest you in a sarcastic comment?
要我諷刺你一下嗎？
Some cheese?
要起司嗎？
Honey, why is the Bruce Springsteen CD in the Cat Stevens case?
甜心，為什麼布魯斯史普林斯汀的CD 會放在凱特史帝文斯的盒子裡？
If I can't find the right case, I use the nearest one.
如果我找不到正確的盒子 我會隨手拿一個盒子來裝
-Where is the Cat Stevens CD? -The James Taylor case.
-凱特史帝文斯的CD在哪裡？ -詹姆士泰勒的盒子裡
-Where is that CD? -I'll save you time.
-那張CD在哪裡？ -我幫你節省一些時間
Two hundred CDs, not one of them in the right case.
那200張CD 沒有一張放在正確的盒子裡
Okay. No need to panic. Deep breaths, everyone.
好吧，不需要慌張 大家深呼吸
We'll just have to put the CDs in their right cases.
我們只需要把CD 放在正確的盒子裡
If we do that, we should come up with some kind of order.
那麼做的話 應該能將CD排好
We have to talk this through.
我們得談一談這件事
Oh, my God, you have such problems! I feel so terrible for you!
天啊，你們真的有問題 我為你們感到難過
All right. Okay, I'm sorry.
好吧，對不起
You're both focusing on this uncomfortable thing.
你們兩個 滿腦子都是這件令人不舒服的事
Change the subject.
改變一下話題
Get him talking about something else.
讓他談別的事
Yeah, that makes sense.
對，那挺有道理的
Maybe you need his advice on a work problem..
或許你在工作上有問題 需要他的建議…
-I could do that. -Good.
-我可以那麼做 -很好
The Miami Vice soundtrack? Really?
邁阿密天龍的原聲帶？ 真的嗎？
They were just giving those away at the store.
那是唱片行的贈品
In exchange for money.
我得拿錢去換
Hey.
嘿
I really don't know what to tell you.
我真的不知道該跟你說什麼
Maybe Joey could help you out with your big work problem.
或許喬伊可以幫你 解決工作上的大問題
-What? -Yeah, Joey, she's..
-什麼？ -對，喬伊，她…
Rachel's got this big work problem. It is a head-scratcher.
瑞秋工作上有個大問題 那真的很傷腦筋
Know what? If we're gonna make dinner, we're gonna have to leave.
你知道嗎？我們想趕上晚餐預約 就得馬上出發
Yeah, Joey, maybe you could help her out.
對，喬伊 或許你可以幫她
-Okay. -Oh, and you know what?
-好吧 -你知道嗎？
While you're helping solve this problem..
你幫忙 解決這個問題時…
you might want to do something with your hands. Like, off the top of my head..
或許你想手邊找些事來說 我是不小心想到的…
maybe put the CDs in their right cases.
譬如說將CD 放到正確的盒子裡
Here we go.
來吧
So you have a big work problem?
你工作上出了大問題？
Yeah. It's, uh..
對，那是…
Yeah, it's, uh..
You know, it's nothing.
真的沒什麼
Okay.
好吧
So I think I'm gonna take off.
我想我該走了
No, wait, Joey, it is. It's something. It's..
不，喬伊，等一下，我有問題 它真的很嚴重，是…
It's my boss.
是我的老闆
-Yeah? -Yeah. And, uh..
-是嗎？ -對，跟…
And my baby.
跟我的寶寶
Yeah?
是嗎？
My boss wants to buy my baby.
我老闆想買我的寶寶
What? Oh, my God!
什麼？我的天啊
I know, I told you, it's a really big problem!
我知道，我跟你說過了 這真的是個大問題
-He wants to buy your baby? -Can you believe that?
-他要買你的寶寶？ -你能相信嗎？
-That's crazy. -That's what I told him!
-那太瘋狂了 -我就是那麼跟他說的
-How did this even happen? -Well, I'll tell you.
-怎麼會發生這種事？ -我會告訴你
See, my boss and his wife, they can't have children, so..
我老闆跟他太太 他們不孕，所以…
And then when we were at the Christmas party..
在耶誕派對上 我們碰到了面…
he got drunk and said to me, "Rachel, I want to buy your baby."
他喝醉了跟我說 「瑞秋，我要買下你的寶寶」
When you said it was a problem about your boss and the baby..
你說你老闆跟寶寶 有問題的時候…
I figured it was about maternity leave.
我以為 你是指產假的問題
Oh. Yeah.
對
Yeah, that would have been a much simpler problem.
對，那樣子 問題簡單多了
-Oh, hello. -Oh, it's you. I see you everywhere.
-哈囉 -是你，我走到哪裡都會碰到你
I'm Jim. Jim Nelson.
我是吉米，吉米尼爾森
Hi, Jim-Jim Nelson. I'm Phoebe-Phoebe Buffay.
嗨，吉米吉米尼爾森 我是菲比菲比布非
-We've seen each other a lot lately. -Yes.
-我們最近常見面 -對
Maybe we'll see each other at dinner tomorrow. Around 8:00?
或許明天晚餐時我們也能碰面 八點可以嗎？
Well, maybe we will.
或許會吧
Mona?
蒙娜
Okay, if I were a salmon shirt, where would I be?
如果我是鮭魚色襯衫 我會在哪裡？
Upstream.
上游
Damn, nobody's here for my good ones.
該死 沒有人聽到我的好笑話
I am so sorry I spilled wine all over your shirt.
抱歉我把酒 灑到你的襯衫上
-It's okay. -No, it's still wet.
-沒關係 -不，它還是濕的
Let me get it out before it sets. I have something you could wear.
我得把它拿去洗乾淨免得留下印子 我去找件衣服借你
Here.
拿去吧
I don't know if I want to wear a woman's shirt.
我真的不想 穿女人的襯衫
-That's a man's shirt. -Awfully pink.
-那是男人的襯衫 -可怕的粉紅色
It's not pink!
那不是粉紅色
Honey, we are so meant to be together.
甜心 我們注定要在一起
-We both have the Annie soundtrack. -Honey, both yours.
-我們都有安妮的原聲帶 -甜心，那都是你買的
Hey, great advice on that Joey thing.
謝謝你給我關於喬伊的建議
-The work problem? -lt was perfect.
-你是工作的問題嗎？ -它真的是太棒了
It felt like he was my friend.
我覺得他是我的朋友
-What problem did you say you have? -Oh, that's not important.
-你說你有什麼問題？ -那不重要
The point is, I think everything's gonna be okay.
重點是 我想一切都會沒事
May I help you?
需要我效勞嗎？
You think you can just buy my friend's baby?
你覺得你可以買走 我朋友的寶寶？
Isn't it funny how we kept meeting? It's as if someone wants us together.
我們一直巧遇真的很有趣吧？ 那就像是有人要我們在一起
Someone does. Me.
沒錯，那就是我
Witty banter. Well done. Good.
聰明的傢伙，做的好
-Tell me a little bit about yourself. -Okay. I'm a masseuse.
-跟我談談你自己 -好吧，我是按摩師
-And I used to work at this place.. -Do you like to party?
-我以前在這個地方工作… -你喜歡參加派對嗎？
I like parties.
我喜歡派對
You're wild, aren't you?
你很狂野，對吧？
-Yeah, I guess. A little. -Ain't no thing. I'm wild too.
-對，我猜是有一點 -那沒有什麼，我也很狂野
So anyway..
總之…
I've lived in New York, somewhat wildly, I guess..
我住在紐約 我猜那有點狂野…
for, well, since I was 14.
我從14歲就住在這裡
I'm sorry. I'm staring.
抱歉我盯著你不放
It's just that you have the most beautiful eyes.
因為你有雙最漂亮的眼睛
-Oh, stop it. -And your breasts!
-別說了 -還有你的胸部
Okay.
好吧
Look, you're coming on a little strong.
聽著，你有點太快了
I'll give you the benefit of the doubt.
我會解開你的疑慮
The universe wants us to be together.
宇宙要我們在一起
Why don't we start over? You can tell me about yourself.
我們為什麼不開始呢？ 你可以跟我談談你自己
-All right. -Okay.
-好吧 -好吧
I write erotic novels..
我寫小孩子看的…
for children.
色情小說
-What? -They're wildly unpopular.
-什麼？ -它們非常不受歡迎
Oh, my God!
我的天啊
Also, you might like to know I have a Ph.D.
或許你會想知道 我是個博士
-Wow! You do? -Yep. A pretty huge..
-真的嗎？ -對，它真的很大…
All right.
夠了
-Hey. -Joey, honey, listen.
-嘿 -喬伊，聽我說
Thanks for talking to me yesterday. It meant a lot.
謝謝你昨天跟我談 那對我來說意義重大
Not a problem. Just so you know..
別客氣 我得告訴你…
that guy won't be bothering you about that baby thing anymore.
那傢伙不會再為了寶寶的事 來煩你了
-What? -Let's just say I took care of it.
-什麼？ -就說我已經解決了問題
Let's say more.
我們得談一談
Don't worry. I told him, very nicely:
別擔心，我好好地跟他談過
"You don't go buying people's babies! So back off!"
「你不能買別人的寶寶 別鬧了」
-What? -What?
-什麼？ -什麼？
No, no, no!
不
He doesn't want to buy my baby! I made that up!
他不想買我的寶寶 那是我編出來的
What? Why?
什麼？為什麼？
So we would have something to talk about!
我們才有話題聊
And you couldn't think of anything else?
你想不出來 別的借口嗎？
You said your boss wants to buy your baby?
你說你老闆 要買你的寶寶？
You yelled at my boss! I'll lose my job! What am I gonna do?
你對我老闆大叫 我會被開除，我該怎麼辦？
You could always sell your baby.
你可以賣掉你的寶寶
I can't believe you brought my boss into it! I'll be fired!
我不敢相信你會去找我老闆 我會被開除
-You lied to me! -Well, she told me to!
-你騙我 -是她要我那麼做的
Chandler has two copies of Annie!
錢德有兩張安妮的原聲帶
Oh, my God!
我的天啊
-Ross! -Hello!
-羅斯 -哈囉
What are you doing?
你在做什麼？
Not touching myself, if that makes anyone less uncomfortable.
希望你們聽了能夠釋懷 我沒有自摸
Okay, then. I'll call you.
好吧，我會打電話給你
Morning. You wanted to see me?
早安，你找我？
Please, come in. Have a seat.
請進，坐下
-Look, Mr. Zelner.. -It's best I speak first.
-聽著，佐納先生… -讓我先說吧
Yeah.
好吧
Lee from Human Resources is here as a witness to our conversation.
人事部的李 將是我們談話的見證人
Oh, God.
天啊
If I in any way implied that I wanted to buy your baby..
如果我有暗示過你 我想買你的寶寶…
I am sorry. Okay?
我很抱歉，好嗎？
Last week, when I asked you when your due date was..
上星期我問你 你的預產期是什麼時候…
I certainly did not mean that I felt that I was "due" your baby.
我並沒有那個意思 要告訴你我想「買」你的寶寶
I want to be very clear..
我希望清楚地告訴你…
that I understand that it's your baby..
我瞭解 它是你的寶寶…
and it is not mine to purchase.
我不能買下它
Well, as long as we are clear about that.
只要把話說清楚就好了
There it is.
到了
-Not your regular cleaners. -I know.
-這不是你常去的洗衣店 -我知道
That creep goes there. I had to find a new one.
那個怪胎會去那裡 我得找新的洗衣店
I have to find a new bank, adult bookstore, grocery store..
我還得找新的銀行 成人書店，雜貨店…
-What? -A new grocery store.
-什麼？ -新的雜貨店
The universe said I'd meet a nice guy. I got that?
宇宙說我會認識一個好男人 那是真的嗎？
When I get up there, I'm gonna kick some ass.
我上天堂後 一定會痛扁它
You'll meet someone. If I can meet a great guy, so can you.
你會認識某人的 如果我能找到好男人，你也可以
Yeah, we both can. And we both will.
對，我們都可以，也都會做到
-You didn't have to come in. -You kidding?
-你不必進來 -你在開玩笑嗎？
This is where they get out stains. This is like Disneyland for me.
他們在這裡把衣服洗乾淨 對我來說這裡就像是迪士尼樂園
I'm gonna be over here watching the dance of the clean shirts.
我要到這裡 看乾淨襯衫跳舞
Excuse me. I think you dropped..
對不起 我想你掉了…
-Wow! -What?
-哇 -什麼？
Sorry. You're just so incredibly beautiful.
抱歉 你真的是美得不可思議
Well, I'm sorry about that too. But what are you gonna do?
我也這麼覺得 但又能怎麼辦呢？
Don't think I'm crazy, but I was meant to pick this up.
別覺得我瘋了 我本來是要幫你撿這個
-Do you believe in that kind of thing? -A little.
-你相信那種事嗎？ -有一點
Now you're talking.
你說的對
-Want to go for coffee? -I'd love to. Let me tell my friend.
-你要去喝咖啡嗎？ -我很樂意，我去跟我朋友說一聲
An ink stain! Can I watch how you get this out?
是墨水印子 我能看你把它洗乾淨嗎？
She must have left.
她一定是離開了
-So? What happened? -It's all gonna be okay.
-所以呢？發生了什麼事？ -沒事了
They're so happy I'm not suing, I got an extra month paid maternity leave.
他們很高興我不告他們 我還能多放一個月領薪產假
So long as I understand the money should not be construed..
只要我知道 那些錢絕不是…
as a down payment on this or any other child.
這個寶寶 或其他寶寶的訂金
Ralph Lauren is going out of their way..
羅夫羅蘭 真的想盡辦法…
to show they're not in the baby-buying business.
要證明 他們不是販嬰集團
-Give us a minute? -Kicking me out of my living room?
-能讓我們獨處一下嗎？ -你要把我踢出我家的客廳？
Yeah.
對
I'll be in there.
我會在那裡
I'm sorry I lied to you. I was just trying to make things..
抱歉我騙了你 我只是希望事情…
I know. I know.
我知道
It kind of worked.
你的方法的確有效
I don't know about you, but I haven't thought about our thing.
我不知道你是怎麼想的 但我一直沒想到我們的事
Yeah, you're right.
對，你說的對
Yeah. It's kind of been like "us" again, a little bit.
對，我們又恢復了 「朋友」的樣子
-Yeah, I know. I've missed that. -Me too.
-我喜歡，我很想念那段時光 -我也是
I haven't thought about how I put myself out there..
我沒有想到 自己怎麼會…
and said that stuff. How you didn't feel the same..
跟你說那些話 你跟我的感覺不同…
and how it was really awkward.
那真的很可怕
My gynecologist tried to kill me.
我的婦產科醫生想殺我
Item J437-A.
編號是J437-A
Color: winterberry.
顏色，冬莓色
Hi, listen. Come here. Come..
聽著 過來，來吧…
I'm so, so sorry about yesterday.
關於昨天的事我很抱歉
But what did I tell you about leaving your key outside the door like that?
但我不是跟你說過 不要在門外留備份鑰匙嗎？
I mean, you're lucky it was me and not someone else.
還好那是我 不是別人
I guess lucky is too strong a word.
我想那麼說太重了一點
Anyway, Mona, I'm really, really sorry. It's just..
總之蒙娜，我真的很抱歉 那只是…
Listen, you don't have to apologize. I understand why you were there.
聽著，你不必道歉 我瞭解你為什麼會去那裡
-You do? -Yeah. You still have feelings for me.
-真的嗎？ -對，你對我還有感覺
To be honest, I still have feelings for you.
老實說 我也對你還有感覺
I wish we could work it out, but we can't.
我希望我們能復合 那是不可能的
It's too complicated with you and Rachel and the baby. I just..
你跟瑞秋還有寶寶的事 太複雜了，我只是…
It just wasn't meant to be.
那個人不該是我
Oh, God. You're right.
天啊，你說的對
Ross, we have to be strong.
羅斯，我們得堅強
Okay, I'm gonna go.
好吧，我得走了
Can I? To remember you?
我能留下它來懷念你嗎？
No.
不行